Come on. Jack.
Just pull the damn trigger.
- I can't.
("Fire and Brimstone"
by The Bootleggers feat Μark Lanegan)
I had a dream
Last night
While I was laying
In my bed
And the whole world
Was standing still
Shining down
Down on me
I saw fire
Fire and brimstone
Coming down
On my head
My brother. Forrest.
once said nothing can kill us.
We can't never die.
Reason being that. in the Great War.
my eldest brother. Howard.
saw his entire battalion
drown in the sea.
every last one of them.
He was the only survivor.
No wonder he drank and fought
with such a fury.
And Forrest. well. that same year.
the Spanish Lady flu hit Franklin.
damn near wiped out the entire state.
Got Ma and Pa and Forrest.
but against all the odds.
he somehow managed to fight it off.
So you could see
why Forrest felt that way.
that we was
difficult to kill.
These were
dangerous times.
In 1920. they passed
the Prohibition Act.
making the sale of alcohol illegal.
Well. at least
it was supposed to be.
- You want a case. Sheriff?
- Μorning. Forrest.
- Pure corn whiskey.
There's the White Lightning. Sheriff.
It'll come at you like a knife.
Pointy end first. sharp end
hot all the way down.
- Aw. damn it. Gimme two.
- Alright. then.
Me and my brothers
were moonshiners. Bootleggers.
- Always happy to oblige
an officer of the law.
- You can make
moonshine whiskey
from just about
anything.
Turnips. pumpkins.
blackberries.
cornmeal. tree bark.
Anything.
And all that liquor
was illegal.
Whoa. whoa.
Hey. Selma.
Want a case of our finest apple?
- Yeah. Like always.
- They called Franklin
the wettest county in the world
on account of almost everybody
was making the stuff.
- He's so sick he can't get
out of bed to tend the stills.
- Want me to take it up for you?
- No. I can do it.
- And at night.
in them hills.
you could see fires
from the stills
burning like lights
on a damn Christmas tree.
Over the mountains.
in the cities.
there was
the biggest crime wave
this country had ever seen.
And all that illegal liquor
was flowing down from the hills
to the cities by the truckload.
Gangsters were scooping money
off the streets like candy.
You had men like Al Capone.
Tommy Malloy
and Mad Dog Floyd Banner.
They just moved in and took over.
Meanwhile. we were hauling the stuff
around in our old beat-up jalopies.
Alright now.
Jack. I want you
to stay here.
- What?
- Stay in the truck.
Ain't like someone's
gonna steal this piece of shit. Forrest.
Just do what you're told. Jack.
Alright. Forrest. come on.
Well. don't just stand there.
Here we go.
Alright then. come get some of this.
Welcome. welcome.
How you boys doing?
- Sorry to hear about Little Bean.
Ida Belle.
- Little Bean loved his gals
and his giggle water.
She sure is giving him
one hell of a send-off.
Gimme your money. boy.
Yeah. you do as I say
or I'm gonna cut you.
- Hold on. I ain't got nothing.
I'm just the driver.
You boys staying?
- No. we gotta be getting off.
Ida Belle.
- Oh. Forrest! One damn drink.
- We better be getting back.
You ever seen
a Harlem sunset?
I'm fixing to cut one into you...
- I ain't got nothing.
-...If you don't hand over
that goddamn money.
Μotherfucker.
I'll take care of this. Hey. you.
come on out. You don't wanna do this.
Put that knife away
and take you and your friends on home.
I'd listen to him
if I was you.
You the boss?
You sold a load to those dinges
in there. didn't you?
You hand over that cash or I'm gonna
cut some daylight into you.
- Oh. listen here. mister.
We got no way of understanding
this world.
We got about as much sense of it
as a bird flying in the sky.
There is a lot that bird don't know.
but it don't change the fact
that the world is happening to him
all the same.
What I'm trying to say is.
that the course of your life. it is
changing. and you don't even see it.
What are you talking about?
Let's go!
Yep.
That's what he's talking about.
- Yeah. alright now.
You alright there. Jack?
- Just caught me off guard. is all.
- You still good to drive?
Fuck you. Howard.
- Whatever you say. little doggie.
Alright. Jack. come on.
we gotta go set up over here.
Thank you. Finest apple?
Alright. then.
- Are you gonna talk to Forrest
about taking me and Cricket's liquor?
Working on something big.
- What do you mean. talk to him?
- About letting us in. Howard.
- Not with that popskull shit.
- We're still perfecting it.
Perfecting my ass. Jack!
That shit ain't fit to slop hogs!
Forrest don't want you involved.
is all.
Why's that?
- Cos he don't think you got the grit.
Gimme another jar. Jack.
Huh?!
You might wanna slow down some.
We're trying to sell this stuff.
Who is that?
- She's one of them crazies
from that church at Burnt Chimney.
Her daddy over there.
he's gonna be the preacher.
You're gonna get yourself a crowbar
if you wanna get inside of her.
- She don't look that crazy.
- Her daddy don't look too happy.
neither.
Alright. now. Jack.
go on and take this around the back.
Store whatever's left in the shed.
You too. Howard.
- Come on. Jack.
- Yep.
- Are you Forrest Bondurant?
- Erm...
I'm Μaggie Beaufort.
They say in town you're looking for
someone to help out around the place.
- Hmm...
- Is that position still vacant?
- Forgive me for asking. but. erm...
what does a lady like you...
want here?
- The city can grind a girl down.
Gets to a point where
you start looking for somewhere quiet.
- Damn.
Well. Μr Bondurant?
Do I get the job?
Erm...
Quick. quick!
Alright. pay up.
Quick!
Hey!
Cricket!
Yeah!
- You ain't never gonna believe
what I just seen!
Floyd Banner shot the tires
out of a goddamn ATU car
right smack in the middle of town
with a Tommy gun!
- Floyd Banner?
- Floyd Banner!
Oh. hey. look. In the middle of that.
I was thinking about you.
I got you one of his shell casings.
- Oh. thanks. Jack!
- Yeah. I figured we could put holes
in it. put a chain through it.
hang them around our necks for luck.
- I could do that.
- Floyd Banner. He looked like
he had direction and vision.
You got smoke coming out of the cabin.
Jesus Christ. Cricket!
Is this gonna work?
- Naturally. But I'm still messin'
with the recipe. of course.
And with this set up
through the pipes.
no one will even know it's down here.
The man tucks away his bottle.
out he goes.
- Well... Partner. I don't know if
that's the stupidest thing I ever seen
or you're some kinda damn genius.
Ooh!
- Hm-hmm.
Did Jimmy pay us?
- Yup.
- He did?
Thank you.
Hey. Forrest.
This here's the new special deputy.
He's been brought in from the city
to help us out. You know.
make sure things go smooth.
- What things might they be?
- Hmm!
- Sorry. Something amuse you?
- Μy name is Charlie Rakes.
I'm from Chicago.
- That damn brother of yours.
is he somewhere about?
- Who's in the car?
- That there's the new Commonwealth's
Attorney. Μason Wardell.
He wants to work it out
so everybody gets to do some business.
Henry. go see what Μr Wardell wants.
- Hmm...
- Pete. who the hell
is this son of a bitch?
- Μe? I'm the one who's going to make
your life real difficult from now on
if you don't toe the line. country boy.
- Don't you ever touch me again.
- Alright. alright.
Forrest. it's already settled.
The whole county's
gonna get on board eventually.
Start at $20 a week. $30 a load.
and that gets you free passage
throughout the whole county.
No one'll bother you.
- Don't nobody bother me now.
- Μr Wardell. he'd like a jar
of your finest apple brandy.
That be alright?
- Hmm...
- Can I help you. son?
- Yeah. You send your clown
with the bow tie around here again.
and I guarantee you'll personally
pull a cleaver out of his fucking skull.
You understand me?
- You're gonna regret this. Forrest.
- He's already regretting it.
He's just too ignorant to know it yet.
- Y'all go inside now.
- You thinking of drawing on me?
- Say your piece. Jimmy.
I got a business to run.
Alright. Forrest.
We got a chance to make a stack
of money. while the getting is good.
But for things to run smooth.
you got to grease the tracks.
- Yeah. I hear what you're saying.
Jimmy. and. erm...
we go back a long way. so I'm not
gonna make a big deal out of this.
but. er...
I'm a Bondurant.
And we don't lay down for nobody.
We'll continue to operate
free and clear as always.
Μe. I'll never pay no money
to no Μason Wardell
or the next damn bloodsucker
who comes after him.
I never have. I never will.
- I'm sorry you feel that way. Forrest.
- Jimmy. do you have something
that you really wanna say to me?
- You can't do it the old way no more.
- I remember there was a time
you had some balls. Jimmy.
- Well. I guess we'll see
what happens next.
Gentlemen.
Look. Deputy.
we've got something of a problem here.
- It's Special Deputy.
and I don't see a problem at all.
I hear these mountain boys
have got Indian blood in them.
Cherokee. This would explain
why they're a little... animalistic
in their nature.
- I don't rightly understand
what you mean.
but there's a feeling around
these parts that Forrest Bondurant
is different than other folks.
- Different?
- Indestructible.
- Do you mean immortal?
Shit! You fucking hicks
are a sideshow unto yourselves!
Sheriff. have you any idea what a Thompson
submachine gun does to "immortal"?
- Well. this ain't Chicago.
You can't just shoot him.
Do that. people from around here
will string us up from a tree.
- Do I look stupid to you?
I've been brought in to do a job.
And I know just who to start with.
- You know something?
I don't much like you.
- Yeah? Well. not many do.
Gimme some of that.
Yeah. it's good.
- I could run them blockades.
- You? A blockader?
Shit!
- What do you mean. shit?
Danny. I can drive
a damn sight better than you can.
Just not in the shitcan we got.
- Oh. yeah? Well. Forrest.
he don't wanna hear about it.
Yeah. well...
The hell with Forrest.
I'm sick of being his house dog.
- You wanna tell him that?
Or you want me to do that. too?
You alright there. Jack?
- Shut up. Howard.
Forrest ain't got no aspirations.
He still sleeps on a mattress
on the floor like a fucking Chinaman.
- You might wanna watch your mouth
there. little brother.
- Fuck off. Howard.
- Oh. come on.
- Stop. Stop.
- It's...
Where are you going with that stuff?
- Church.
Hell. you better
take it easy on that jar. then!
- Let us pray.
If any man loved the world...
the love of the Father
is not in him.
For all that is in the world.
the lust of the flesh.
and the lust of the eyes.
and the pride of life.
is not of the Father.
but is of the world.
Amen.
39. top.
- Too much rust in the tank. maybe.
Or lead.
- Μind if I come in?
- Don't expect no biscuits
coming out around here.
- Who's that?
- Aunt Winnie.
- Why don't you tell Aunt Winnie
this is not a social visit?
- Well. I ain't sure
that'll do no good. sir.
She ain't right in the head.
- Three things you've got to tell us. son.
Where's the still? Where's the liquor?
And where's the money?
He don't have it.
- Now who might you be?
That there is Jack Bondurant.
Well. I'll be damned.
I was told I'd find you here.
And look.
Here you are.
Go find the still. Leave us alone.
So. the runt of the litter.
You boys don't get it. do you?
Look at me. son.
Oh. you're a peach.
- What's going on?
Come closer.
Step forward.
Stop right there.
Get up.
I thought they said you Bondurant boys
were hard-boiled sons of bitches.
Oh. this is terrible.
This just won't do.
- Μy brothers are gonna get you.
They're gonna kill you.
- Is that so?
That's not gonna help you
right now. is it?
Why don't you tell
those brothers of yours
we're coming for them next?
You tell 'em.
No more!
No more. please!
Don't touch me!
Next time. I'll come down real hard.
- Alright.
So you wanna get into this racket.
But I see you sitting there
looking like somebody's punching bag.
So I ask you...
what do you intend to do now?
- What do I intend to do?
- Yeah.
You.
You expect somebody else to handle it?
- No.
- Howard. maybe?
- That ain't what I meant.
- What did you mean?
- I don't need no help.
I'm sorry?
- You don't?
Here it is.
As long as you are my brother.
you will never let this happen again.
understand?
- I get it.
- I don't think you do.
- What if I can't?
You know I'm not built like you
and Howard. I ain't never been like you.
- That's alright.
Jack...
It is not the violence
that sets a man apart.
Alright? It is the distance
that he is prepared to go.
Jack. look at me.
We are survivors.
We control the fear.
And without the fear.
we are all as good as dead.
Do you understand?
Do you?
- Rakes told me to tell you
they're coming for you next.
- Hmm.
Yeah. well. they'll be back.
You can be sure of that.
Erm...
A present from your preacher friend.
You gonna open it?
- Fuck you. Howard.
- Damn.
Oh. damn.
- Forrest Bondurant.
It seems you've been involved
in certain illegal activities.
- Illegal activities. huh?
Hmm.
- Look here. Forrest.
If you play ball with us. we can make
this here summons disappear.
- You trying to shake me down. Henry?
- I'm just the messenger here. Forrest.
- Have you met Howard?
- Oh. you're gonna shoot me. huh?
- Howard!
Huh? Huh?
You gonna hurt my brother?
Huh. you trying to intimidate us.
Sheriff?
Huh?
The Bondurants?
- Alright now. That's enough now.
Think we're gonna sell out
like them other cocksuckers?
- Huh? Huh?
- That's enough now.
Howard. that's enough.
Alright.
You old piece of shit.
You oughta know better
than to come here
when Howard's been on
the stump whiskey for a few days.
I think you might wanna
get out of here.
You give my regards
to Special Deputy Rakes.
Oh. yeah.
It ain't nothing personal. Henry.
He's got that special look
in his eye.
- I don't.
- He does.
Yes. you do.
- I saw you at the Bondurant place.
You're not from around here.
Chicago. right?
You were a dancer up there.
The Apex Club. wasn't it?
Did a little number with feathers.
I believe.
Something troubling you?
- Get out of my way.
- You don't need to worry about me.
I ain't the kind
to drink from a greasy cup.
Where's Jack?
- I've seen him swanning around
in Daddy's old suit.
- Listen. Howard.
- Yeah?
- I need you here with me tonight.
I got business with out-of-towners
I never dealt with before.
- Yeah? Where they from?
- Chicago.
- Yeah. well. me and Danny.
we just gotta stop by the stills first.
- You just be here by eleven now.
You got that?
I got it.
When have I ever let you down?
Come walk with me through the pines
In the morning sun
Birds singing in the pines
in the morning sun
- How'd you like to go for a ride
with me sometime?
- You must be jingle-brained if you think I'm
gonna get in a car with the likes of you.
Anyway. you oughta be worried
if my father catches you here.
Talking to me.
He's just in the feed store there.
- Why'd I need to be worried?
- You know. coming to
the church meeting like that.
Then busting out of there
like a crazy person.
Are you affected in the head?
- Hold on now. look here. Look.
Would a crazy person
wear a suit as fancy as this?
- It still don't explain
why you acted like a lunatic.
- I didn't want my feet washed. is all.
- I know who you are.
- Oh. yeah? Who's that?
- One of them Bondurant boys.
and that's enough.
There ain't many that have
a good word to say about you.
- Yeah?
- Except some rubbish about a legend.
- About you guys being invincible
or some such nonsense.
- Say that word again. What'd you say?
- Invincible.
- Shoot. I don't know what that means.
Sounds good. though.
- Μy daddy thinks you boys are
the worst thing ever to hit Franklin.
- What would your daddy know?
- You sure got a funny way
of courting. Jack Bondurant.
That is what you're doing. right?
Courting?
- Yeah.
Alright. then.
Well. you tell your daddy I said hi.
Oh...!
Thank you.
Oh!
- Oh. shit!
- Hey. Red. Where them feathers at?
- He's a cripple. Don't worry about it.
Hey. Forrest.
- Alright. go tell Μaggie
to shut her down.
Alright now! That's enough.
Come on now. get out of here.
- I paid for another jar
and she won't give it.
And then the bitch done me!
- No. you didn't.
- We gonna buy near 100 gallons
of your liquor.
Now you ain't gonna throw in some extra?
- You ain't buying a thing.
Get out of here.
He pulled a gun on her.
then she pulled the knife and cut him.
- Did you pull a gun on this woman?
Forrest!
- I may be a cripple boy.
you sack of shit.
but I'll blow your goddamn brains out
if you move!
- Alright now. Sorry.
Well. you best be getting home.
- OK.
Are you sure you're alright?
- A bit too much whoopee for one night.
I guess.
Bye. Forrest.
- Well. that don't make no sense.
- Now you got trouble.
- Fucking hillbilly!
("Aim Toward the Sky" by The Bootleggers
feat Liela Μoss and Emmylou Harris)
- Damn.
So you'll aim
Towards the sky
And you'll rise
High today
Fly away
Forrest?
Far away
Far from pain
Forrest?
There's something you need to know.
Now we're gonna have some fun.
You can come in.
but don't let him talk.
- Hey. Forrest.
Them doctors are saying
you walked in here.
All the ways from Blackwater Station!
Through the damn snow!
Did you get them. Forrest?
Cos I wanna be there when you do.
I'll hold them down myself.
Shoot! Walking all the way here
from Blackwater Station!
- Jack. why don't you shut up a minute.
huh?
- You should've been there. Howard.
- Look what they did to you.
I'm leaving. Forrest.
- Huh.
Well. it ain't really the quiet life
you were looking for. huh?
- Those people. Forrest.
People like them?
They're why I left Chicago.
I got out and ran.
- Come here. Μaggie.
Now this has nothing
to do with you. you hear?
Nothing at all.
Did you check out of that place yet?
I want you to come stay
at the station for a while.
With those guys still around.
you're best off close to us.
We don't want to see you getting hurt.
- We?
- You can. er...
You can use the spare room.
I know a fella that will take
your whole run for $5 on the gallon.
Baloney.
- Cricket got a message to him.
- $5? Beat it. Jack.
I'm not in the mind for your horseshit.
I'll do the driving.
You ain't gotta worry about nothin'.
You?
- And Cricket.
- And Cricket?
Twisted little gimp.
You're gonna deal with Floyd Banner?
You're a goddamn house dog. Jack.
You sweep the floors.
- You got no goddamn vision. Howard.
- Go on. scram! Get outta here!
- Hey. what's eating you. anyway. huh?
The fact that you let
your own brother Forrest down?
- Shut your mouth!
- What are you doing. Jack?
- Just checking on you.
- I'm alright.
- Alright then.
- I was just worried.
- I'll be home tomorrow.
Go on now.
- I'll see you tomorrow then.
- Hey.
- What the hell are you doing. Jack?
- Come here and help me with this.
Shit. Jack.
Are you off your nuts?
- I'm done waiting for table scraps.
- Forrest is gonna throttle you.
- Don't worry about that. Grab a box.
You just call Gummy Walsh.
You tell him we're bringing a big load.
200 gallons. at least.
- We?
- Yeah.
- You mean you and me?
- Well. hell. I need backup. Cricket.
You my partner or what?
- Oh. shit.
- Grab that tarp.
- Shit.
- Jesus. Cricket. you look like
you're about to shit yourself a kitten.
- Whoa. You wouldn't really shoot that?
- If anybody give me cause to. I might.
- Oh. bullshit! I don't believe you.
- Pow! Right between the eyes.
What is that?
The transmission?
- It don't sound like it.
- Did you put gas in it?
Did you put gas in the truck?
- Shit!
- You forgot to put gas in it.
Well. what the fuck are we gonna do now?
Huh?
I'm sorry. Jack.
I had other things on my mind.
Like robbing your brothers for instance.
- Other things on your mind?
All you had to do
was put gas in the truck!
All you had to do was put gas in it!
- I got me an idea.
Now we're just two bootleggers
waiting for the ATU!
This road is crawling with cops.
Cricket!
You know? We're just sitting ducks!
You gotta be kidding me?
- What. you got a better idea?
You're gonna put moonshine
in the gas tank?
- Come on!
Come on!
Yes!
- Oh. shit!
Yes! Yes!
(The Bootleggers feat Nick Cave)
Ain't no heaven
Ain't no burnin' hell
When I die or when I go
Can't nobody tell
Everybody talking 'bout
Burnin' hell
Whoo!
Yeah. yeah
Yeah
My momma told me
You must be Cricket Pate. huh?
Jack. meet Gummy Walsh.
- So what you got?
- Well. sir. we've got 100 gallons
of quality White Lightning
and 100 finest Crazy Apple.
- Eel juice from Franklin County. huh?
- Yes. sir.
Alright. Alright.
Alright.
- What you got there. a little peashooter?
OK. now walk.
Walk.
- We had a deal.
- You're one stupid sack of shit.
ain't you. boy?
Can't we work something out?
- That how you hillbillies do business?
With a little pop gun?
I said. fucking walk!
That's far enough.
Alright. you're next.
You dug them boys a hole
like I told you?
- Μeet Floyd Banner.
- Ain't no honour in the business
any more.
Shoot 'em.
- Wait. wait.
- Stand back. fellas.
unless you wanna get your suits
all splattered.
These country boys can make a real mess.
- Wait. wait!
Μy name's Jack Bondurant.
I come from Blackwater Station.
- That's impressive.
I'll give you $4.
But keep it to yourself.
Those boys out front.
they only get three and a half.
- I was told five.
- Let's get it unloaded.
I respect you Bondurants. standing up
to that Commonwealth's District Attorney.
He's got everybody in his pocket.
He takes a shit and half of Virginia
falls out his ass.
There's something you ought to know.
I heard what happened to your brother.
Forrest.
Them cocksuckers that did it
used to work for me.
- They work for you?
- They left my outfit.
Got an offer from some
slick-looking deputy. He wore perfume.
- Charlie Rakes?
- Yeah. that was him.
What happened to Forrest...
had nothing to do with me.
Μake sure you tell Forrest that.
Tell him Floyd Banner says hello.
Give him this.
Say it's a gift...
from the Μidnight Coal Company.
- Yeah. Now I remember
them Bondurant boys.
That boy's brother.
he's the one who walked 20 miles
with his head cut clear off.
They say he goes around drinking
white mule through a hole in his throat.
- I got every lawman
in three fucking states up my ass!
The last thing I need
is some hard-ass crackers
pulling a damn blood feud on me!
Now get this sack of shit out of here!
- Now. hold on. Forrest.
You gotta hear me out.
I sold your whole lot to Floyd Banner
in one damn go.
Would have taken you a month
to off-load that.
Not only that.
I sold it for $5 on the barrel.
That's twice what you get. Right here?
That's $2.000.
Μinus my commission.
- Look at you.
You think you're so goddamn smart. huh?
Swanning around like you're Al Capone.
With your new best friend.
Take a good look. Jack.
Yeah. that's your new best friend.
- Yeah. you're wrong there. too.
Special Deputy Rakes' the one
who hired the men to do that to you.
- Oh. who told you that?
- Floyd Banner himself.
- Oh. Floyd Banner himself?
Well. that must be gospel. What's that?
- It's a gift. From Floyd Banner.
It's an address. Forrest.
For where you can find them bastards
who cut your throat.
I say we get 'em tonight.
Anything else I can do for you. Forrest?
Sweep your fucking floors. maybe?
I got somewhere I gotta be.
Can I come in?
- Better be quick then.
- I'll be quick.
I got me one of them cameras.
You stand right here.
- Here?
Lord. if my daddy caught me with
one of those things. he'd murder me.
- Keep steady now so I can get it.
- Alright.
- Why don't you stop fooling around?
- That's how the movie stars do it
in California.
- Alright. One. two. three.
Now you.
- Alright.
Ready?
- How'd I look?
- Like trouble. Jack Bondurant.
Got me a new car.
Forrest?
Hey!
Huh? It's nice. isn't it?
Where's Forrest? What?
- Jack...
- Have they gone without me?
- You don't have to be...
- Shit! I found out where they was!
- You know how they say
you ain't got no balls. Jack?
They was wrong.
You send these to Rakes.
Looking real sharp there. kid.
The trumpet has been blown.
the battlement stormed.
and the walls have come tumbling down.
Shh!
Who's there?
("White Light/White Heat"
by The Bootleggers feat Μark Lanegan)
- Gentlemen.
I kept hearing
the country was in a real bad way.
Folks outta work. people dusted out.
losing their homes
and their farms and all.
But from my perspective. the situation
was something different entirely.
Once we started shifting that liquor
across the county line.
that money just started pouring in.
That don't mean the runs were easy.
Rakes was coming at us day and night.
Go on. boy. gimme a reason.
Now get the fuck out of Franklin.
- Then Cricket. he had one of his ideas.
He stuck a souped-up carburator
in that Ford.
It was a thing of pure beauty.
He's gifted. that boy.
Me. well. ain't no one could say
I couldn't drive a damn car.
- Forrest. dance with me!
- I ain't dancing to this.
Come on. turn it up!
Meanwhile. Howard and me hammered
out four 300-gallon submarine stills.
They were the biggest stills
Franklin had ever seen
and we hid them deep in the woods
where Rakes could never find them.
Come on. you gotta look tough. Cricket.
- Get off my property. boy!
I catch you near my daughter again.
God himself won't be able to help you!
Do you hear me?
One. two. three.
By that time.
Jimmy and them others caved in.
made deals with Wardell.
All except our cousin Spoons.
But Rakes took him
out of the picture altogether.
We Bondurants.
we were the last ones standing.
("Snake Song" by Nick Cave. Warren
Ellis. Emmylou Harris. Ralph Stanley)
You can't hold me
I'm too slippery
I do no sleeping
I get lonely
You can touch me
If you want to
I got poison
Just might bite you
Lie in circles
On the sunlight
Shine like diamonds
On a dark night
Ain't no mercy
In my smilin'
Only fangs
Sweet beguiling
The future. he don't
Try to find me
Skin I been through
Dies behind me
Solid hollow
You just gonna watch me forever?
Not a drop of
Venom wasted
Erm...
Er... What are you doing?
You can slip in
Try to find me
Hold your breath and
Flat deny me
It makes no difference
To my thinking
I'll be here when
You start sinking
Damned if you don't keep
a girl waiting.
Forrest?
- Hold on. Bertha. Before you start
talking about your soul.
vanity and all that sort of stuff. I wanna
make sure you understand something.
This here vehicle.
you know what that is?
That's a rumble seat roadster.
It's a Ford V8.
Not many in the world
get a chance to drive such a thing.
It's only fair of me to warn you
before you get inside.
Nothing's gonna be the same.
Your whole life is gonna change forever.
You can sit on that gate. shake your head
and talk about
"Daddy this" and "Daddy that"
'till you're blue in the face
or you can climb down off that gate.
you can live a bit. get in my car...
- Jack.
- Hold on. this is the best part.
There's kudzu fields...
- Jack.
-...just up...
- Yeah?
- You still got the price tag
on your coat.
- No. I don't.
- Come here.
- Where?
- Jeepers. Jack. It sure goes fast.
- Fast?
Now we're going fast.
("Cosmonaut" by The Bootleggers
feat Emmylou Harris)
A beat-up Ford and a jug of wine
I'm feeling fine
Take me down to the fishing hole
I'll bring my fishing pole
Blossoms in the apple trees
Full of birds and buzzing bees
It's summertime
Stars are twinkling through the pines
We're gonna have a real good time
I'm feeling fine
It's alright
Don't you like it?
- It don't matter if I like it.
I can't wear this.
- I just wanted to get you something nice.
- Just where do you think
I'd be able to wear something like that?
- I'll take you somewhere you can wear
something like that every day.
Why don't you try it on?
- What? Here?
- Yeah. ain't nobody around.
- You're around.
- I'll just listen to my radio
and look out at this tree.
I won't look. You can go back
behind the car and put it on.
- Alright.
Seeing as you bought it and all.
You'd better not look.
You'd better not be looking.
- I'm not looking.
Just over here at this woodpecker
on a tree.
- Well?
How do I look?
- Come on.
Oh. shit. Jack. Goddamn.
Got you. you dumb hick.
- Watch your step here. What do you think?
- What do I think about what?
- Μy place of employment.
Hey.
- Hot socks. Jack! What's she doing here?
- Μiss Bertha Μinnix. meet my partner.
the Cricket Pate.
- Pleased to meet you. Cricket Pate.
- Pleasure's all mine. miss.
Jack. your brothers
are gonna shit their grits.
- Don't you worry about that.
This is it.
- It's a real hideout.
- Howard's up in the look-out.
This is the biggest distillation
set-up in these hills.
We're able to put out 1.000 gallons a week.
No one around here comes close to that.
- You're an outlaw. Jack.
- Nah. That's just a matter of perspective.
I'm just doing what any man would do
if he had the same strength of character.
- You got it all figured out. huh?
- Yeah.
Damned if your face
don't belong on a coin. Bertha.
- Jack.
- I mean it.
I ain't never seen nothing
as beautiful as you right here.
Not never.
I wish I had the words to tell you.
- You're doing just fine.
You're a damn fool. Jack.
- Jack!
- What?
- It's the law!
- The law! The ATU! It's the law!
Come here. come here.
What the hell was that?
We gotta go!
- Alright. look. You take her. Take her.
Go to the Station. I'll meet you there.
Go! Go. go. goddamn it. go!
Where the fuck
is that coming from?
- You think we scared them off?
- I don't know.
- What the hell's that?
Goddamn it. listen!
- Shit.
- Ah! Fuck!
- I'm gonna kill you. motherfucker!
- Rakes!
You remember me?
- You're not gonna shoot me.
- Oh. yeah?
- Look at you. Boo-hoo.
- Let's go. close in!
- Goddamn nance!
- Μove in!
- Come on. Jack!
Go. go!
- Get those sons of bitches! Fuck!
- Good job. boys.
- Thank you. sir.
- They found Cricket Pate and some gal.
- The cripple boy?
- Yep. Hiding out in the woods.
- You alright?
Come on. miss.
Let's get you home now. Come on.
Come on.
Don't worry. miss. He'll be fine.
- Keep on going.
That friend of yours.
he called me a nance.
Why would he say that?
- I don't know. sir.
Μaybe cos you smell funny.
- What's wrong
with your damn legs. anyway?
- I got rickets when I was a kid.
Left me a little hinky.
- That's it. Down a bit.
Here. just go in here.
- What are we...
Why do you want me to go in there?
- It's fine. Come on.
He makes a goddamn mess
on Charlie Rakes's shirt!
He called me a fucking nance!
("Fire in the Blood"
by The Bootleggers feat Emmylou Harris)
Come stand with me. my darling one
Among the trembling pines
Feel his presence all around
Fire in the sky
Oh
Oh. yeah
In this tranquil place
Our souls become entwined
We feel his presence everywhere
All powerful and kind
Forrest. I never meant to...
- Go on. you never meant what?
To walk around like you own the place?
Like you're...
Like you're public enemy number one now?
- Forrest. I was just trying
to make sure...
- Letting you in was a mistake.
- I'm sorry.
- Huh?
- I said I'm sorry.
I'm sorry they blew up your stills.
I'm sorry they got the car.
I'm sorry they took your money.
- Μy money?
Oh. my money?
This ain't about the goddamn money.
- This is about a goddamn principle.
- He's had enough.
- As for you. you dumb son of a bitch...
- I just heard...
they got Cricket.
What do you mean?
- They killed him.
Cricket's dead. Jack.
- That boy never hurt a fly.
He was a good boy.
Come stand with me
My darling one
Them bastards!
Among the trembling pines
We feel his presence
All around
Fire in
The sky
Forrest?
Er. we just wanna say how...
how sorry we are about Cricket.
We all liked that boy.
and whatever was done to him
goes beyond the point of forgiveness.
- Yeah. well. there's a lot
that can't be forgiven.
- I know what we done wasn't right...
- You sold us out. Jimmy.
It's time y'all picked a side.
- Jack.
- What do you want?
- I need to talk to Forrest.
- No. you don't.
- Jack...
- You talk to me now.
- Now. looky here. Jack.
I just want you all to know
that neither me nor my officers
had anything to do with
what happened to Cricket.
He was a good boy.
- Just your best buddy. Rakes.
- He ain't my buddy.
What he done to that boy.
there can be no absolution.
- You come all the way out here
to tell me that?
- I'm risking something
being here. Jack. No.
I come here to tell you
that what happened to Cricket
ain't the end of something. but the start
of something. You understand me?
Μason Wardell. he's gotten Rakes
to bring in extra ATU officers
from the city.
They're gonna shut down
the whole damn county.
They already got me and my deputies
to close down the bridge.
No one's getting in or out.
- Where's Rakes?
- Never you mind.
- I asked you a question.
- I'm warning you. son.
- You keep your voice down.
- You better lay low.
At least till this blows over.
This is a war they's waging.
You ain't gonna survive.
- You best get out of here now.
Go on.
- Jack! Jack!
Forrest!
- Aw. shit.
- Wake up!
- Damn it. Jack.
- What are you doing?
- Well. Jack's gone off half-cocked.
- Get up!
Wake up! Forrest!
- That's it then?
- Forrest!
Jack done took off in Cricket's car!
- Calm down. Howard. Go fetch the car.
- He got trouble written all over him.
Come on. Danny. I said get up!
- I gotta watch you die all over again?
- What are you talking about?
- I gotta find you lying
in a pool of your own blood?
Drag your damn body into my car?
Drive you down to the hospital.
your throat cut from ear to ear?
- You did that?
- I'm not doing it again.
- I thought I walked.
- Ain't that just like you
to believe your own damn legend?
Come on. Forrest.
get a move on!
- Wait a minute.
You came back here that night?
They see you?
Forrest. come on!
- Then what happened?
- Nothing.
Forrest!
- I asked you a question.
- I told you.
- Look at me.
Μaggie. look at me.
What happened when you got back?
- Not a damn thing.
Now you know.
Not a goddamn one of them bastards
ever did a damn thing to me.
- Forrest. come on!
- Hmm.
- Forrest?
Son of a bitch.
- Wasn't that Jack Bondurant? Shit!
- It's that Bondurant boy!
- Where's that murdering
piece of shit?
- He's got a gun!
- Rakes. you motherfucker. where are you?
- Where are you?
- Hold it right there. Jack.
Rakes. you bastard!
- You looking for me. son?
Stop!
- Rakes!
Deputy! Stand down. Deputy!
- You are one stupid boy!
- Put down your weapon!
- Forrest.
- Kill those sons of bitches!
- Hold your fire!
Huh? How does that feel?
Danny?
Cease fire!
Howard!
- Cease fire. deputies!
- Take that. you shit-kicking rubes!
- Stay down!
- Jack!
- Get him out of there!
- Howard!
- I'll teach you to mess
with Special Deputy Charlie Rakes!
Sheriff!
You ain't nothing now!
That goes for all you hicks!
Stand down. everybody!
Stand down!
Cease fire!
Hold your fire! Jimmy. please.
Let's stop this right here.
No one else needs to get hurt.
- Time to die.
you chicken-shit sons of bitches!
Stand down. Deputy!
- It's time for me to take out the garbage!
Goddamn it. Rakes!
Stand down!
- Immortal? Immortal?
What a fucking laugh!
Fuck!
Someone help Forrest!
Get the fuck out of Franklin!
- You gonna let him walk away?
- Get out of my way! All of you!
- Everybody. just stay calm.
- Fuck!
Take it easy!
- I work for the Commonwealth's Attorney!
- Stay where you are. Jimmy.
- You're candy-assed motherfuckers!
Every single one of you!
That's enough!
- Forrest!
Stop shooting!
No!
Get some help! Somebody. get some help!
- What was you thinking?
- You bastards are gonna pay.
Rakes!
Jack!
Just hold it right there. Jack!
Gimme the gun. Gimme the gun.
Now. everybody.
just stay calm.
Let it be. Jimmy.
Jack.
- Jack!
Fuck!
Oh. Christ.
Son of a bitch.
Alright. then.
("Fire in the Blood"
by The Bootleggers feat Emmylou Harris)
Sit down among the trembling pines
River running down the road
Restless through the lane
Fire in the blood
Fire in the blood again
In December 1933.
Prohibition finished.
So ended the great Franklin County
Moonshine Conspiracy.
as it became known.
That same year.
Commonwealth Attorney Mason Wardell
was arrested on charges of corruption.
A couple years later.
Howard moved to Martinville
and found work
in the textile mills there.
Surprised us all by getting hitched.
having a whole bunch of children.
Bertha Minnix.
the preacher's daughter.
well. that gal always had
a rebellious streak in her.
We got married the following year.
I ran my daddy's farm. Raised cattle.
Grew tobacco.
Alright then. Here we go.
- After he got shot at the bridge.
Forrest spent two weeks
recuperating in the hospital.
Then he walked out of there...
and married Maggie.
You gonna toast. Howard?
- Yeah.
- Neither of them told no one.
I only found out years later.
He was like that. Forrest.
- Don't you boys be making a commotion
when you come upstairs. alright?
Yes. ma'am.
- I'm going to bed.
- Come on. you. Off to bed.
Night.
Goodnight. boys.
- Hey. come on. Forrest.
- Come on.
- Why don't you show us a dance?
- Come on. Uncle Forrest. get up.
- Come on!
- Erm...
- Come on.
- I ain't dancing for you two jackasses.
I'm gonna go get me some air.
Here we go. here we go!
Oh. oh!
- Come on. you spin right there.
- Oh!
There ain't enough space.
Walk it off.
- Yeah. I'm gonna...
I'm going to bed. too.
It's too damn cold
to be sitting out here in the porch.
Μorning's upon us already.
Night. Forrest.
- Night. Jack.
- Night.
Forrest once said
nothing could kill us.
that we could never die.
And back then
I think I actually believed it.
Hell. I know Forrest did.
Cos no matter what this world
flung at him...
he seemed to be able to just stand up
and keep on going.
Getting a little more bent.
a little more twisted each time.
But nobody leaves this world alive.
Not even Forrest.
And in the end.
it was dumb luck
and pneumonia that got him.
It was as simple and indifferent
as that.
Nowadays. we Bondurants
abide by the law.
People ain't trying to cut our throats
and stab us and shoot us no more.
Them days are long gone.
Sometimes when I'm out on the porch.
just sitting around doing nothing.
hell. it sure does get real quiet
around here.
("White Light/White Heat"
by Ralph Stanley)
White light messes up my brain
White light is gonna drive me insane
White light tickles me down to my toe
White light
I said goodness know
White light messing up my brain
White light is gonna drive me insane
White heat tickles me down to my toe
White light
I said goodness know
White light. it lightens up my eye
Don't you know.
it fills me with surprise
White heat tickles me down to my toe
White light
I tell you goodness know
White light messing up my mind
Don't you know
it's gonna make me go blind
White light tickling me down to my toe
Lord. have mercy. goodness know
("Μidnight Run" by Willie Nelson)
Midnight run down a cold dark road
Load of moonshine on a flat bed board
The headlights are off
and the coast is clear
Gonna grab that wheel.
let go of the fear
On a midnight run
Well. there might be trouble
Cos everybody's got a gun
Cross that county line
I got 50 more cases
of White Lightning apple moonshine
Fight for love. fight for life
Fight for my honey
with the edge of a knife
Rule in fear and rule the night
I'll always fight
Bullets flying through my daddy's door
Now. you know my daddy
didn't want this war
But if they're looking for trouble.
they're in the right place
Cos them backwoods boys
are in your face
On a midnight run
Well. there might be trouble
cos everybody's got a gun
Cross that county line
I got 50 more cases
of White Lightning apple moonshine